Newspaper Guild of Albany, Local 34; Records apap005
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Newspaper Guild of Albany, N.Y., Local 34 Records1936-1989
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Newspaper Guild of Albany, N.Y.
apap005
5.25 cubic ft.
Chartered in 1934, as the Tri-City Newspaper Guild of Albany, Schenectady, and Troy, the Guild signed its first contract with the Albany Times Union in 1937. The Albany Guild's last strike in 1964 formed the basis for The Ink Truck, the first published novel of William Kennedy, who was one of the strikers.
Administrative History
The Newspaper Guild of Albany, N.Y., Local 34 was chartered on March 20, 1934, as the Tri-City Newspaper Guild of Albany, Schenectady, and Troy, N.Y. as well as nearby cities. In 1937, the guild won its first agreement and the first Newspaper Guild agreement in upstate New York when it signed a contract with the Albany Times Union. The Albany Guild's last strike in 1964 formed the basis for The Ink Truck, the first published novel of William Kennedy, who was one of the strikers. The local began as a union of reporters and editors, but over the years other newspaper occupations have been organized as the guild has subsumed independent unions. Currently, janitors and drivers, as well as employees from the business office and sales and circulation departments are represented by the guild. Although the guild has confined most of its activities to the tri-cities, it has opened offices in Hudson and Glens Falls, New York.
Scope and Contents
Contains executive board and membership minutes, 1936-87; unit minutes, 1942-87; bulletins, 1936-84; contracts, 1937-89; and organizing and litigation files, 1935-88.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into 4 topical file series.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were loaned to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by the Newspaper Guild of Albany, Local 34 and subsequently preservation photocopied as a part of the Harry Van Arsdale, Jr., Labor History Project. The originals have been returned to Local 34.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Newspaper employees -- Labor unions -- New York (State).; Journalists -- Labor unions -- New York (State).; Newspaper publishing -- New York (State) -- Albany.; Labor unions -- New York (State) -- Albany.; Labor unions -- New York (State) -- Glens Falls.; Labor unions -- New York (State) -- Hudson.; Minutes; Correspondence; Newsletters; Contracts; Labor; Albany, New York; Schenectady, New York; Rensselaer County, New York; American Newspaper Guild.; Independent Committee of the Albany Times Union.; American Newspaper Guild.; Newspaper Guild of Albany, N.Y.; Kennedy, William, 1928- Ink truck.
- Minutes, 1936-1987; 1; 1 cubic ft.
  - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1936-1946 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 1)
  - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1947-1952 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 2)
  - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1953-1962 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 3)
  - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1963-1965 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 4)
  - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1966-1969 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 5)
  - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1970-1975 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 6)
  - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1976-1978 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 7)
  - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1979-1984 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 8)
  - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1985-1987 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 9)
  - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1936-1946 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 10)
  - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1947-1951 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 11)
  - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1952-1957 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 12)
  - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1958-1961 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 13)
  - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1962-1967 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 14)
  - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1968-1973 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 15)
  - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1974-1977 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 16)
  - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1978-1979 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 17)
  - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1980-1983 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 18)
  - Knickerbocker News Unit Meeting Minutes, 1942-1956; 1966 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 19)
  - Times Union Unit Meeting Minutes, 1942-1951 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 20)
  - Glens Falls Unit Meeting Minutes, 1985-1986 (Box 1 (1-Minutes), Folder 21)
- Organizing and Litigation Files, 1936-1984; 2; 2.66 cubic ft.
  - Capital Newspapers--Injunction Against Chester W. Vanderbilt (strike initiation), 1964 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 1)
  - Capital Newspapers--NLRB Charges, 1968 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 2)
  - Capital Newspapers--NLRB Case (interference with union activity), 1988 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 3)
  - Capital Newspapers--NLRB Case (bylines), 1985 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 4)
  - Glens Falls Newspapers--Contract with Albany Printing Pressmen, Assistants, and Offset Workers No. 23, 1983 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 5)
  - Glens Falls Newspapers--NLRB Case, 1984/1987 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 6)
  - Glens Falls Newspapers--NLRB Case, 1984 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 7)
  - Glens Falls Newspapers--Organizing, 1968/1969 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 8)
  - Glens Falls Newspapers--Organizing, 1973; 1978; 1983-1984 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 9)
  - Glens Falls Newspapers--Organizing, 1984 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 10)
  - Hudson Unit--Decertification, 1987/1988 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 11)
  - Hudson Unit--NLRB Case (unfair labor practice), 1986 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 12)
  - Knickerbocker News--Contracts with Press Circulation Union, 1950/1951; 1953; 1956; 1958 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 13)
  - Knickerbocker News--Merger with Albany Times Union, 1960 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 14)
  - Knickerbocker News--NLRB Case, 1939/1942 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 15)
  - Knickerbocker News--NLRB Case, 1942 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 16)
  - Knickerbocker News--NLRB Case (Scott Wanhope), 1945/1946 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 17)
  - Knickerbocker News--NLRB Case, 1949/1950 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 18)
  - Knickerbocker News--NLRB Case, 1950 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 19)
  - Knickerbocker News--NLRB Case, 1958 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 20)
  - Knickerbocker News--Organizing, 1947; 1949-1951 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 21)
  - Knickerbocker News Circulation--NLRB Petition, 1957 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 22)
  - Knickerbocker News Circulation--Organizing, 1950; 1952 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 23)
  - Knickerbocker News Circulation--Organizing, 1957/1958 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 24)
  - Knickerbocker News Commercial--NLRB Case, 1942; 1944 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 25)
  - Knickerbocker News Editorial Employees--NLRB Case, 1938 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 26)
  - Non-Communist Affidavits, 1950; 1957-1958 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 27)
  - Organizing--General, 1952; 1954-1955 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 28)
  - Press Company Merger--NLRB Case, 1937/1941 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 29)
  - Saratoga--Organizing, 1957 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 30)
  - Schenectady--Organizing, 1952/1953 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 31)
  - Schenectady Gazette--Organizing, 1937/1939; 1954; 1982 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 32)
  - Schenectady Sun, 1938/1939 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 33)
  - Schenectady Union Star--Organizing, 1936/1939 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 34)
  - Times Union--Contracts with Circulation Independent Committee, 1946/1959 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 35)
  - Times Union--NLRB Case, 1941 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 36)
  - Times Union Circulation--NLRB Case, 1938; 1940 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 37)
  - Times Union Circulation--NLRB Case, 1940 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 38)
  - Times Union Circulation--NLRB Case on Independent Committee, 1940/1941 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 39)
  - Times Union Circulation--NLRB Case, 1956/1958 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 40)
  - Times Union Circulation--Organizing, 1944/1947 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 41)
  - Times Union Circulation--Organizing, 1958 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 42)
  - Times Union Independent Committee--Organizing, 1945 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 43)
  - Troy Record--Organizing, 1937 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 44)
  - Troy Record and Times Record--Organizing, 1946; 1948; 1954 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 45)
  - Union Star--Organizing, 1958; 1965-1966; 1969 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 46)
  - Union Star--Take-Over by Capital Newspapers, 1969 (Box 1-6 (2-Organizing and Litigation Files), Folder 47)
- Grievance Files, 1952-1982; 3; 0.17 cubic ft.
  - Bulletin Board Problem, 1976 (Box 1 (3-Grievance Files), Folder 1)
  - Funiciello, John--Grievance, 1974 (Box 1 (3-Grievance Files), Folder 2)
  - Graphics Editor--Grievance, 1976; 1981-1982 (Box 1 (3-Grievance Files), Folder 3)
  - Grievance Procedure, 1952-1953 (Box 1 (3-Grievance Files), Folder 4)
  - Kniskern, Paul--Grievance, 1982 (Box 1 (3-Grievance Files), Folder 5)
  - Lowenkron, Henry--Grievance [missing 12/18/2005 acs], 1970 (Box 1 (3-Grievance Files), Folder 6)
  - Riley, George--Grievance, 1959 (Box 1 (3-Grievance Files), Folder 7)
  - Rosenblatt, Linda A.--Grievance, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (3-Grievance Files), Folder 8)
  - Schick, Timothy--Grievance [missing 12/18/2005 acs], 1981-1982 (Box 1 (3-Grievance Files), Folder 9)
  - Scott, Janet--Grievance, 1953-1954 (Box 1 (3-Grievance Files), Folder 10)
- Bulletins, 1936-1988; 4; 0.4 cubic ft.
  - Bulletins, 1936-1940 (Box 1 (4-Bulletins), Folder 1)
  - Bulletins, 1941 (Box 1 (4-Bulletins), Folder 2)
  - Bulletins, 1942-1943 (Box 1 (4-Bulletins), Folder 3)
  - Bulletins, 1944-1946 (Box 1 (4-Bulletins), Folder 4)
  - Bulletins, 1948-1949 (Box 1 (4-Bulletins), Folder 5)
  - Bulletins, 1951-1957 (Box 1 (4-Bulletins), Folder 6)
  - Bulletins, 1958-1959 (Box 1 (4-Bulletins), Folder 7)
  - Bulletins, 1961-1966 (Box 1 (4-Bulletins), Folder 8)
  - Bulletins, 1967-1968 (Box 1 (4-Bulletins), Folder 9)
  - Bulletins, 1969-1972 (Box 1 (4-Bulletins), Folder 10)
  - Bulletins, 1975-1984; 1988 (Box 1 (4-Bulletins), Folder 11)
- President's Files, 1941-1972; 5; 0.33 cubic ft.
- Empire State District Council Records, 1942-1952; 6; 0.66 cubic ft.